LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

Highly experienced full-stack web developer with **over three years** of success in developing, deploying, and optimizing customer-centric applications. Experienced with **JavaScript (ES6+)**, **Node.js**, **React**, **Angular**, **TypeScript**, **HTML5/CSS3**, **EC2**, **and NoSQL/SQL databases**. Possesses a strong understanding of **server architecture and latency optimization**, **caching**, **CI/CD pipeline**, **API integrations**, **and UI/UX design**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer | ORBIT SPORTS DATA | Oct 2021 - Present

A Dubai based B2B startup providing real-time data and reporting services, took part in developing customer match statistic and reporting applications for various sports, resulting in a 40% user adoption increase and 65% revenue rise, significantly improving user experience and expanding product usage.

- Constructed cross-platform customer match statistics applications using Angular and reporting
 applications for various sports with React, Redux, and responsive design.
- Employed **Jest** and **Cypress** automatic testing tools to reduce manual testing time by 70% and enhance software quality.
- Developed **backend APIs** and **microservices** with **Node.js** and **Nestjs** Framework, optimized **SQL** queries and **Redis** cache communication, resulting in a 35% performance boost.
- Implemented new features and made critical **architectural** decisions, increasing **security** and decreasing **debugging** and development time by 60%.
- Formulated **adapters for B2B integrations**, enabling the company to provide reporting services to multiple third-party clients concurrently, resulting in a 55% rise in revenue.
- Administered CI/CD and server deployment on AWS to ensure cross-continental low latency and high availability, improving customer satisfaction and loyalty.

Freelance Developer and Designer | Mar 2019 - Oct 2021

- Increased contracts for PetrossonBygg by 25% by building and deploying a React-based website.
- Boosted engagement for **Issa Touma's Le Pont Organization** by 30% through creating a new **WordPress** online gallery.
- Built a full-stack application utilizing Trello's REST-API and Docker containers.
- Constructed a **GraphQL Apollo** ePortfolio backend with a version control system for the database.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Volunteer | Humanitarian Relief | Archdiocese of Alexandretta | Aug 2016 – July 2019

- Designed databases utilizing **SQL, UML, and DBLC** technologies to support the Disaster and Humanitarian Relief program aided by international organizations like Aid to the Church in Need (ACN) Poland.
- Created a **C#** application **(Excel to VCF Converter)** to facilitate quick and easy import of contacts to mobile devices, reducing manual input time.
- Enhanced **team's speed** from 250 to 1K Aid-Units/hr for a 5-person distribution team using **Arduino**, allowing for more efficient distribution of aid.

EDUCATION

- University of Aleppo, Computer Engineering.
- **Projects:** Connect 4 electronic game and a full-stack manual image moderation system that utilizes AI for pre-filtering.

SKILLS

- Front-End Development: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, Angular, React, Redux, React Native, styled-components, Bootstrap, Material UI, Firebase, Vuejs.
- Back-End Development: Node.js, Express, REST APIs, Socket.IO, TypeORM, Nestjs, Git, GitHub, NoSQL/SQL databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB), Docker, Jest, Puppeteer, Design Patterns, PM2, NGINX, EJS, Plesk, Linux, AWS, ESLint, GraphQL, Apollo, Webpack, RabbitMQ.
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Maya.

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent).
- Arabic (Native).